terraform an infrastructure as code tool that can provision resources in the
terraform 一种基础设施即代码工具，可以在
cloud from simple declarative code when
云中构建应用程序时从简单的声明性代码
building an app in the cloud you may find yourself using the graphical user
在云中配置资源 您可能会发现自己使用
interface of your favorite cloud provider
您最喜欢的云提供商的图形用户界面
clicking on buttons and paying for products just like you would on an
单击按钮并像您一样为产品付款 一个
e-commerce site the only drawback of this approach is that it's complete and
电子商务网站，这种方法的唯一缺点是它完全和
total chaos you might click a thousand different buttons to get your vm
完全混乱，您可能会单击一千个不同的按钮来正确配置您的虚拟机
configured properly but what happens when you need to
，但是当您需要
reproduce the same thing again in the future
在未来再次复制相同的东西时会发生什么
terraform provides a way to build change and version infrastructure
terraform 提供了一种方法
safely and efficiently by representing your infrastructure
通过使用 hashcorp 配置语言或可选的 json 表示您的基础架构
and all that settings with the hashicorp configuration language or optionally
和所有设置来安全有效地构建更改和版本基础架构
json think of it like a human readable blueprint that can execute and
将其视为人类可读的蓝图，可以执行和
automate everything you do in the cloud it's free and open source
自动化您在云中所做的一切它是免费和
and the first step to get started is to install the cli on your local system
开源 开始的第一步是在本地系统上安装 cli
then from your project create a file ending in tf
然后从您的项目中创建一个以 tf 结尾的文件
at the top we have a terraform block that controls global settings for
在顶部我们有一个 terraform 块来控制
terraform itself most importantly we can define providers
terraform 本身的全局设置最重要的是我们可以在此处定义提供程序
here which are like plugins that can connect to different cloud providers
，它们就像可以连接到不同云提供程序的插件，
like aws google cloud azure etc below that we
例如下面的 aws google cloud azure 等 我们
have a provider block which gives terraform the necessary credentials to
有一个提供程序块，它为terraform 提供必要的凭据以
connect to our google cloud account from there we can create actual cloud
从那里连接到我们的谷歌云帐户，我们可以使用资源块创建实际的云
infrastructure using a resource block it takes a type as its first argument which
基础设施，它将类型作为其第一个参数，
corresponds to a product on google cloud then a custom name to identify it as the
对应于谷歌云上的产品，然后是自定义 名称将其标识为块内的
second argument inside the block we can customize the
第二个参数我们可以自定义
settings of the resource like its machine type
资源的设置，例如其机器类型
zone and anything else you can imagine now that our infrastructure is defined
区域以及您现在可以想象的任何其他内容，因为我们的基础设施被定义
as code we can run terraform init to initialize the project
为代码，我们可以运行 terraform init 来初始化项目，
then terraform apply to make the actual changes to google cloud
然后 terraform apply 要对谷歌云进行实际更改，
it'll require a confirmation before making the changes then after it's
需要在进行更改之前进行确认
complete the terraform show command can be used
完成后， terraform show 命令可
to inspect the current state of the infrastructure what's awesome
用于检查基础架构的当前状态 令人敬畏的
is that as we add more resources to the configuration terraform keeps track of
是，当我们向配置中添加更多资源时，terraform
the changes or diff similar to a version control system like
跟踪更改或差异，类似于 git 之类的版本控制系统
git just run terraform apply again to deploy any changes to the configuration
只需运行 terraform 再次申请以部署对配置的任何更改，
now once your startup has failed and it comes time to tear down the project
一旦您的启动失败并且是时候
use the terraform destroy command as the inverse of apply to delete everything in
your configuration file this has been infrastructure as
code with terraform in 100 seconds make sure to hit the like button if you want
拆除项目了 100秒，如果你
to see more short videos like this thanks for watching and i will see you
想看更多这样的短视频，请确保点击喜欢按钮谢谢观看，我会在下一个看到你
in the next one